Jake Dudum

San Bruno, CA 94066 | Phone: **(650) 515-7204** | Email: **jakedudum@gmail.com**

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jake-dudum-45a967185/

Github: https://github.com/JakeDudum | Portfolio: https://jakedudum.github.io/My-Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with CS experience and a life-long passion for solving problems. Highly motivated to learn new technologies and use them to create user-driven applications. Flexible in group environments, able to work on any area of an ongoing project alone or with peers.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Front-End Development, Back-End Development, Database Management, Project Management, Analytical Skills, Debugging, UI/UX

Programming Languages and Frameworks: HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, ReactJS, Node.js, Bootstrap, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, jQuery

PROJECTS

Where2P-GitHub: https://github.com/JakeDudum/Where2p | Deployed: https://jakedudum.github.io/Where2p | Deployed: https://jakedudum.gith

A small app that helps users find bathrooms in the nearby area with the ability to add and read reviews as well. My responsibilities for this project were front-end design as well as firebase integration for user reviews. The application uses HTML, CSS, Javascript (AJAX for API calls), jQuery, Materialize, and Firebase.

Bark-GitHub: https://github.com/JakeDudum/Bark | Deployed: https://tranquil-bastion-82369.herokuapp.com/

On bark users can only see blog posts that are in their own area and only post to that area so everything displayed is relevant to where they are. I was personally responsible for the database used for the project (MYSQL with Sequelize) and all calls to the database from front-end to back-end and back-end to database as well as some client-side javascript. This application uses HTML, CSS, Javascript, NodeJS, MYSQL, Heroku(for deployment along with JawsDB), and various node packages for user authentication, time stamps, and running the server.

Jumble-GitHub: https://github.com/JakeDudum/Jumble | Deployed: https://jumble-dash.herokuapp.com/

This is a project management tool that allows users to create projects with names, budgets(with budgets for each department as well), tasks, and problems and display all of the available data in various charts for the user to then modify or complete as need be. For this project I was responsible for the database and all communication to it as well as some front-end react components and charts. The site is a SERN full-stack application(Sequelize, Express, React, Node) that uses charts js to create charts for all of the data and passport for user authentication.

EXPERIENCE

UC Berkeley Extension San Francisco, CA—Substitute Teacher Assistant

September 2019 - Present

Helped teach students how to code at UC Berkeley Extension's Full Stack Web Development course. Worked alongside fellow TA's to teach students how to use HTML, CSS, JS, jQuery, Node.js, React.js, MySQL, and MongoDB. **Zume Inc** Mountain View, CA—*Pielot*October 2018 - April 2019

Worked as part of a team to deliver food and beverages around the south bay area utilizing time management skills and team communication.

Amazon Fresh Brisbane, CA—Fresh Associate

April 2018 - September 2018

Worked in an Amazon Fresh warehouse picking out customer orders in room temperature areas as well as industrial freezer using safety thermal gear. Employed self management and time management skills to complete all work alone.

Progistics San Bruno, CA— Delivery Driver

May 2016 - October 2017

Delivered Amazon same day packages around the bay area in company provided vehicle. Completed assigned route in a safe and timely manner. Communicated directly with driver dispatch to solve on-road problems with packages.

Papa John's San Bruno, CA— Delivery Driver

December 2012 - January 2016

Worked as part of a team to prepare, make, and deliver food and beverages between South SF and Brisbane utilizing time management skills to complete all deliveries in a safe and timely fashion. Used effective team communication to prepare food ingredients according to food safety standards and maintain sanitary working space.

EDUCATION

UC Berkeley Extension San Francisco, CA— Full Stack Web Development Certificate 2019

May 2019 - August

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

University of San Francisco San Francisco, CA

August 2011 - November 2016

Studied computer science for four semesters and acquired over 24 credits in CS.